Max: I arrived at Madrid airport where I met Paula.
Hola, Soy Max.
Paula: Encantada. Soy Paula.
Max: Paula took me to my hotel, and that evening we went to the centre of Madrid
and it was time for my first test.
I had to order a sandwich and a drink in a bar, then ask for the bill.
I sat down at the bar and I tried to order a beer and a ham sandwich:
Por favor, una cerveza y un bocadillo de jamón.
Waiter: En seguida.
Max: Fantastic! The waiter understood me first time.
My pronunciation wasn’t perfect, but I got my beer and my sandwich.
I really enjoyed it.
But then the more difficult bit.
Asking for the bill… Cuánto es?
Waiter: Seis noventa.
Max: ¿Cómo?
Max: Six ninety.
I understood! Paula gave me eight points for the test.
I was very happy with that.
Next we went out into the street.
Test number two was asking for directions and (very important!) understanding them.
We were in a narrow street, and I had to stop someone and ask them for the nearest chemist, una farmacia.
I stopped a woman.
At first I didn’t understand anything she said!
Passer-by: Siga todo recto y tome la segunda por la derecha.
Hay una farmacia en esa calle.
Max: I asked the woman to speak more slowly.
Passer-by: Todo recto y tome la segunda calle por la derecha DERECHA.
Max: I got it this time, I think.
The second street on the right.
I followed the directions and guess what?
There was a chemist there!
Seven points from Paula.
Test number three.
I wasn’t looking forward to this one.
I had to get a taxi to a famous place in Madrid.
Paula wrote down the name of the place on a piece of paper.
It was the name of the football stadium where Real Madrid play.
We stopped a taxi.
El Bernabéu, por favor.
Taxi Driver: Qué? Adónde?
Max: He didn’t understand me.
I tried again, but he still didn’t understand.
I was desperate, so I said, ‘Real Madrid, Stadium, football’.
Taxi Driver: Ah! El Santiago Bernabéu.
Max: Finally! Paula only gave me five because I ended up using English.
Still, at least I made the taxi driver understand where I wanted to go.
And so to the final test.
I had to leave a message in Spanish on somebody’s voicemail.
I had to give my name, spell it, and ask the person to call me back.
Paula gave me the number (it was one of her friends called Lola) and I dialled.
I was feeling a bit nervous at this point, because speaking on the phone in a foreign language is never easy.
Lola: Deje su mensaje después de la señal.
Max: Er. Buenas noches. Soy Max. Max. M-A-X.
Er…Por favor…llámame esta noche…Oh yes…a las ocho y media er…gracias.
Well, my grammar wasn’t right, but I left the message.
Half an hour later, at half past eight, Lola phoned me.
Success! Paula gave me eight points.
That was the end of my four tests.
Paula was pleased with me.
My final score was seven.
I was quite happy with that.
So, how much can you learn in a month?
Well, of course you can’t learn Spanish in a month,
but you can learn enough to survive if you are on holiday or on a trip.
Now I want to go back to England and try and learn some more.
Adiós!